Robert F. Terrell

Pompano Beach, FL 33062 (317) 258-0488 rterrell25@gmail.com LinkedIn: rterrell25 Website: rterrell.io GitHub: rterrell25

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with extensive experience as a financial analyst. Productive in both team-based and self-managed projects. Dedicated to maintaining up-to-date industry knowledge, including front/back-end web development, JavaScript, React.js, React-Apollo, React-Redux, GraphQL, GraphQL Yoga, Prisma, Node.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, GitHub, and agile methodologies.

EDUCATION

Indiana University

Bachelor of Liberal Studies: Social and Historical Studies

- Bachelor of Liberal Studies GPA: 3.37/4.00
- Upper Level Classes GPA: 3.59/4.00

Wyncode Coding Academy(Full-Time Program)

Curriculum:

- JavaScript, React, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, UX/UI Collaboration, Project Management
- 350 Hours of staffed learning and writing over 5,000 lines of code

Miami, FL

Sept. 2019-Dec. 2019

Bloomington, IN

Aug. 2011-May 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Smart-Scrum-AI

Front-End Developer

- Web Application automating Scrum Master position
- using technologies, such as React.js, GraphQl, Python

Team Lead

- Manage junior developers on front-end development
- Manage GitHub merge conflicts
- update user stories using agile methodologies(trello)

Wyncode Academy

Teaching Assistant/Staff Developer

- Assist students throughout 10-week coding bootcamp
- Help students to troubleshoot coding issues
- Guide and teach students through stand ups as well as Agile methodologies
- Grade homework for students

BFS Capital (Small business lender with operations in the U.S., U.K., and Can.)

Perfect Audit Project Manager

- Oversaw project to automate banking operations
- Worked with tech company Ocrolus to develop rules for automated banking system
- Led testing and development phase, refining system as needed for final production
- Oversaw and approved finalized excel macro used in newly adopted operating system

Pricing Analyst

- Priced merchant applications using pricing algorithm
- Reviewed applicant financials/CCR/CBR via Experian
- Made Final decision as to whether application should be priced and placed with underwriting

UK/US Operations Support Analyst

- Reviewed all US/UK merchant bank/credit card processing statements via Microsoft Excel
- Determined annual revenue/cash flow calculations within Microsoft Excel
- Made Final decision on whether merchants met qualifications for loan/merchant cash advance

Indianapolis, IN

Indianapolis, IN

Nov. 2019-Present

Nov. 2019-Present

Miami, FL Ian. 2020-Present

Coral Springs, FL Mar. 2018-June 2019

Coral Springs, FL Dec. 2018-June 2019

Coral Springs, FL Feb. 2018 – June 2019

REFERENCES

G. Frederick Glass Vice President and Director of Athletics Indiana University Karina Alard Operations Support Manager BFS Capital Scott Steward Software Engineer DMI Management, LLC